Jenn Edge

📅 Gainesville, FL 💌 mrs.jennifer.edge@gmail.com 📞 (352) 474-5432 🕮 JennEdge.com

Director of Engineering and Technology Officer with over 15 years of expertise in software engineering. Scales inclusive, collaborative teams through hiring and coaching. Drives the continuous improvement of people, processes, and products across teams with varying needs to deliver business value.

Experience

Director of Engineering & Technology Officer / Infotech

02/2021 - PRESENT

Manage department of 40+ software engineers through multiple levels of engineering managers to guide development process improvements and technical product direction for multiple product teams, including Software-as-a-Service (SaaS), mobile, and enterprise products.

- Direct \$9.5M of development team capacity to focus on highest-impact projects and release products on-time with no known issues
- Successfully championed platform improvement proposals for \$1.9M of funding and inclusion in a client-owned product, including presenting improvements for Python-based user development platform in community forums for end-user feedback and buy-in
- Guide technical strategy with team leads and architects in building a prioritized technical roadmap to reduce long-term development costs and improve the user experience
- Work across the division with product, business development, and services to determine ownership, resourcing, and technical direction for initiatives

Senior Assistant Director of Software Engineering / Infotech Assistant Director of Development / Infotech

04/2020 – 02/2021

03/2018 - 04/2020

Direct a 3-person mobile development team and a 36-person web development team through 5 engineering managers, scaling teams as needed. Drive successful on-time delivery of cloud-native Software as a Service (SaaS) products and over \$6M in annual enterprise software contracts.

- Expand web team 350% (11 to 39 developers), improving team capacity while maintaining an inclusive culture of collaboration across the division through hiring, onboarding, and coaching
- Coached 3 new managers in the transition from individual contributor
- Define emerging tech strategy for the 300-person company in a 4-person committee
- Plan long-term technical roadmaps and advocate with client owner for upgrades over \$10k
- Delivered a demo for a product expected to generate a new revenue stream; established business requirements with external partners and created a SaaS proof of concept that exceeded expectations; developed in a team of 2 using a serverless microservice architecture
- Won 1st place out of 7 teams judged on our business plan and pitch competition in fall 2018 Empowering Women in Technology Startups (EWITS), a 10-week hands-on entrepreneurial training program at the University of Florida

Co-Founder, Vice President / We Advance Tech Together, Inc. 04/2019 – PRESENT Co-Founded 501(c)(3) non-profit to support local women in tech through community-building.

- Cultivate meet-up growth to over 100 members through social media marketing and events
- Public speaking at conferences, including the 2020 Virtual Grace Hopper Celebration

Senior Lead Software Developer / Infotech Lead Software Developer / Infotech

04/2016 - 03/2018 12/2013 - 04/2016

Led development of web-based software suite through 5 annual release cycles, guiding feature squads from requirements gathering through release. Directed the 4-person tech debt team, prioritizing items to improve developer efficiency, reduce regression, and research technical upgrades.

- Reduced developer time to update models by 75%, saving 15 minutes per update
- 1st place of 13+ teams in 2017 and 2018 hackathons; pitched idea and built a Google Docs addon that saved over \$300k by automating behavior-driven design (BDD) document formatting

Senior Software Developer / Infotech
Software Developer / Infotech
Programmer/Analyst / Infotech

04/2012 - 12/2013

02/2010 – 04/2012

04/2006 - 02/2010

Implemented features in a self-managing agile team of 20+ developers, following agile team practices including test-driven development, pair programming, and continuous integration.

- Designed look-and-feel and built user experience of 7 new UI controls required to meet Section
 508 accessibility guidelines
- Developed back-end services replacing over 400k lines of code for a rewrite from layered monolith to service-oriented architecture

Open Source

Member / .NET Foundation

05/2019 - PRESENT

Contributed to Microsoft Entity Framework 6.2.

• Improved start-up initialization performance by 85% (from 14 seconds to 2 seconds for a model with 600 tables)

Technical Skills

- Python, C#, JavaScript (Vue.js, jQuery)
- HTML, CSS, XML
- AWS: Aurora Serverless, CloudFormation, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, EC2, Lambda
- Traditional and Cloud-Native Architectures
- Test-driven development, CI/CD
- Agile methodologies: Lean, Scrum, XP

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering / University of Florida

GRADUATED 12/2005